<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2017-01-23-world-leading-life-science-and-health-technology-research-all-accessible-from-essex.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2017-01-23-world-leading-life-science-and-health-technology-research-all-accessible-from-essex</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2017-01-23-world-leading-life-science-and-health-technology-research-all-accessible-from-essex.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Essex UK Health Technology Cluster&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/imageedit_1_3094217944_600.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px; height: 170px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essex-based life science and health technology companies can access world-class universities and leading-edge research…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rapid advances in life science and health technologies are being driven by partnerships between industry and universities, as novel research is applied to solving real life problems. And businesses located in Essex – between Cambridge and London – are ideally positioned to access world-leading university research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the latest university ranking, the cities of Cambridge and London together boast 3 of the world’s top-10 universities (based on overall rankings) and 3 of Europe’s top 6 institutions for life sciences and medicine. &lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 450px;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr bgcolor=&quot;#307b33&quot;&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#FFFFFF;&quot;&gt;University Rankings [1]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#FFFFFF;&quot;&gt;University of Cambridge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#FFFFFF;&quot;&gt;Imperial College London&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#FFFFFF;&quot;&gt;University College London&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr bgcolor=&quot;#FEF9E7&quot;&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Overall World Ranking&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; (joint)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr bgcolor=&quot;#D5F5E3&quot;&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Life Sciences &amp;amp; Medicine (European Ranking)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prestigious Research Institutes and Innovation Centres…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Biochemistry at University of Essex&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/UG2011.biochemistry4_700.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 299px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Essex’s location within the UK’s life sciences ‘golden triangle’ (London-Oxford-Cambridge) also provides businesses with easy access to world-renowned collaborative Research Institutes and Innovation Centres. These include the Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute &lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;, which is pushing the boundaries of genomic research, The Francis Crick Institute &lt;sup&gt;[3]&lt;/sup&gt;, Europe’s largest centre for biological research, and the new, highly innovative £55 million Stevenage Bioscience Catalyst &lt;sup&gt;[4]&lt;/sup&gt;, which enables biotech, pharma and medtech businesses to draw upon world-leading expertise, networks, academic support and scientific facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cambridge, London, and nearby Oxford also host 5 of the UK’s 6 Academic Health Science Centres &lt;sup&gt;[5]&lt;/sup&gt; - joint NHS-University ventures supporting the translation of academic research into healthcare solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;And Healthcare and ICT expertise within Essex’s own universities…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;University of Essex&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/DSC_2067edited_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 300px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Ranked amongst the top 2% of world universities &lt;sup&gt;[6]&lt;/sup&gt;, the University of Essex specialises in technologies for the management and transfer of big data, and translational research in the fields of biomedical and health sciences.  Also in Essex, Anglia Ruskin University’s IT Research Institute specialises in medical informatics, imaging, ‘big data’ and the Internet of Things &lt;sup&gt;[7]&lt;/sup&gt;.  Anglia Ruskin places great importance on MedTech collaborations and is working with partners to create three MedTech campuses across the county &lt;sup&gt;[8]&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Providing a thriving culture of research translation and collaboration…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;HealthTech slide&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/IE_HealthTech_Slideshow_logos_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 225px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Given this easy access to world-leading research, and the significance of the wider South East England life sciences cluster, &lt;sup&gt;[9]&lt;/sup&gt; it should come as no surprise that Essex is proving an attractive location for established life sciences businesses, as well as spin off companies from both Cambridge and London Universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Find out more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;../index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;INVEST Essex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to find out more about the Essex UK Health Technology Cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt; QS World University Rankings, 2015/16&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sanger.ac.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.sanger.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[3]&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crick.ac.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.crick.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[4]&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stevenagecatalyst.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.stevenagecatalyst.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[5]&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/news/top-nhs-and-university-alliances-recognised-by-department-of-health&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.gov.uk/government/news/top-nhs-and-university-alliances-recognised-by-department-of-health&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[6]&lt;/sup&gt; THE World University Rankings&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[7]&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anglia.ac.uk/anglia-ruskin-it-research-institute&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.anglia.ac.uk/anglia-ruskin-it-research-institute&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[8]&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.medtechcampus.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.medtechcampus.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[9]&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.us.jll.com/united-states/en-us/Documents/Life-Sciences/2014-global-life-sciences-report-JLL.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.us.jll.com/united-states/en-us/Documents/Life-Sciences/2014-global-life-sciences-report-JLL.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2017-01-11-chesterford-research-park-the-cambridge-life-sciences-cluster-in-essex.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2017-01-11-chesterford-research-park-the-cambridge-life-sciences-cluster-in-essex</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2017-01-11-chesterford-research-park-the-cambridge-life-sciences-cluster-in-essex.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Essex UK Health Technology Cluster&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/EUHeTC_Icon_FINAL.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px; height: 171px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drug discovery &amp;amp; development activities at Chesterford Research Park highlight Essex’s contribution to the Cambridge life sciences cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Robinson Building&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/CRP4,_External_Robinson_Bldg_700.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 299px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Located in Essex but just 15 miles from Cambridge &lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;, Chesterford Research Park is an integral part of the Cambridge biotech cluster. The park is home to innovative companies including Isogenica and Charles River Laboratories, and is a key site within the wider UK life sciences ‘golden triangle’ (London-Cambridge-Oxford), contributing to its impressive track record of technology development and ground-breaking scientific discoveries &lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A leading centre for biotech innovation…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Illumina&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/img5_(Illumina)_2_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 300px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Many of the businesses at Chesterford Research Park are leaders in their fields. AstraZeneca undertakes research and development on the site alongside other high-profile biotech companies, many of which are spinouts from Cambridge University. Cellcentric (discovery of small molecule cancer inhibitors), Isogenica (biologics drug development) and Isomerase Therapeutics (biosynthetic engineering) are all involved in highly specialised drug discovery and development. Oncologica has developed precision oncology testing enabling targeted cancer therapies and Axol Bioscience creates human cell cultures and reagents for research. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accessing ‘top talent’ within the Cambridge Cluster…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Chesterford Research Park&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/Chesterford_RP_1_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 299px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;When, in 2013, Astra Zeneca announced plans to relocate major UK R&amp;amp;D operations from Cheshire to Cambridge, the company cited &lt;em&gt;‘access to world-class talent and opportunities for collaboration’&lt;/em&gt; as key drivers behind the move &lt;sup&gt;[3]&lt;/sup&gt;. Within the Cambridge Cluster, the same advantages are attracting leading businesses to Chesterford Research Park, and Essex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;chesterford-research-park-chosen-for-diabetes-research-laboratory-space#.WHY-0NKLSM8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Arecor&lt;/a&gt;, a leader in formulation technology innovation, is currently in the process of relocating to Chesterford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We selected Chesterford because of the quality of innovative companies already located here, the Park’s location within the Cambridge cluster and the excellent central facilities.  Attracting top talent as we continue to grow is key to our future success and we feel that Chesterford is the ideal location from which we can continue to forge ahead.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Sarah Howell, CEO, Arecor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meeting the needs of growing life sciences companies…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Science Village&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/Chesterford_RP_2_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 299px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;One of Chesterford’s key advantages is its ability to meet the changing accommodation needs of growing life sciences companies on a single site. Chesterford Science Village provides small-scale laboratory and office spaces for early-stage start-up firms, which can then expand by taking on more space in the same location. This flexibility has attracted companies such as the award-winning DRW to the site. A producer of novel point-of-care diagnostic kits, DRW has expanded at Chesterford from start-up to established business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chesterford Research Park also provides space for larger businesses. Domainex, a provider of integrated drug discovery services, recently moved into an existing building on the park, having out-grown accommodation at Cambridge Science Park. Companies including Charles River Laboratories and AstraZeneca have designed and built their own bespoke buildings on the site, which still offers space for further business expansions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Close to Cambridge, with space for growth…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cambridge Cluster’s excellence in life sciences continues to attract the best companies and talent. But within the city of Cambridge, it’s not easy for businesses to find space for growth. Just a few miles away, in Essex, &lt;a href=&quot;http://investessex.co.uk/studies/place-studies/chesterford-research-park&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chesterford Research Park &lt;/a&gt;provides that space, along with all the other advantages of the Cambridge Cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Find out more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;../index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;INVEST Essex&lt;/a&gt; to find out more about the Essex UK Health Technology Cluster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[1] &lt;/sup&gt;Google Maps&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[2] &lt;/sup&gt;JLL, Life Science Clusters Report, 2015 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[3] &lt;/sup&gt;AstraZeneca, 2013&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-12-13-essex-uk-at-the-heart-of-the-greater-south-east-england-life-sciences-and-healthcare-cluster.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-12-13-essex-uk-at-the-heart-of-the-greater-south-east-england-life-sciences-and-healthcare-cluster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-12-13-essex-uk-at-the-heart-of-the-greater-south-east-england-life-sciences-and-healthcare-cluster.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Essex UK Health Technology Cluster&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/imageedit_1_3094217944_600.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; width: 600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Greater South East England’, comprising the South East, East and London regions, is home to Europe’s largest life sciences cluster - sometimes referred to as the London-Oxford-Cambridge ‘Life Sciences Golden Triangle’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Illumina&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/img5_(Illumina)_700.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 300px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Focused on the world-leading university cities of London, Cambridge and Oxford, the cluster serves industry sub-sectors including biotechnology research and development, healthcare, medical &amp;amp; optical equipment manufacturing and pharmaceutical manufacturing. &lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the cluster area, the county of Essex is becoming increasingly popular as a location for health technology companies. A range of local factors is attracting them there, including direct access to Cambridge and London, state-of-the-art research and technology parks, a highly skilled workforce and excellent connectivity to UK and global markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's important to view Essex's attractiveness to health technology businesses within the context of the wider, 'Greater South East' life sciences agglomeration. So what is it that makes this cluster world-class? And which are the universities, business and research organisations that companies can access from an Essex base?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Greater South East England Life Sciences Cluster&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;External Robinson Building&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/CRP4,_External_Robinson_Bldg_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 299px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;From a location in Essex, health technology companies can access a wider life sciences cluster that includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•           &lt;strong&gt;4 of the world’s top-10 ranked universities:&lt;/strong&gt; University of Cambridge, University of Oxford, University College London (UCL) and Imperial College London &lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•           &lt;strong&gt;2,300 other life sciences businesses &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[3]&lt;/sup&gt;, including global leaders such as GE Medical, Smith and Nephew, Roche Products, Merck Sharp, Dohme, GlaxoSmithKline and Charles River Laboratories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•           &lt;strong&gt;5 of the UK’s 6 Academic Health Science Centres&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;sup&gt;[1]  &lt;/sup&gt;and leading medical research institutes including the Wellcome Trust, Cancer Research UK and Public Health England&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•           &lt;strong&gt;The City of London&lt;/strong&gt;, offering specialist business funding solutions for life sciences and health technology companies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The London-Stansted-Cambridge Corridor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Chesterford Research Park&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/Chesterford_RP_2_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 299px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Within the Greater South East England cluster, the 'London-Stansted-Cambridge Corridor' is emerging as a key growth area for life sciences companies. Intersecting Essex, the corridor connects Europe's business capital (London) with the UK's leading technology hub (Cambridge). The corridor's assets include 1,400 life sciences businesses, 37 world-class life sciences research institutes and 40% of the UK population qualified to degree level or above. Within Essex itself, key locations include &lt;a href=&quot;http://investessex.co.uk/studies/place-studies/london-stansted-airport&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;London Stansted Airport&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://investessex.co.uk/studies/place-studies/harlow-enterprise-zone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Harlow Enterprise Zone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://investessex.co.uk/studies/place-studies/chesterford-research-park&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chesterford Research Park&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essex offers distinct location advantages to health technology companies: technologies, skills, space for growth and connectivity. But, just as importantly, it's at the heart of a wider life sciences cluster with truly world-leading credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIND OUT MORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;../index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;INVEST Essex&lt;/a&gt; to find out more about the Essex UK Health Technology Cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] London &amp;amp; Partners – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.londonandpartners.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;londonandpartners.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[2] QS World University Rankings, 2015/16&lt;br /&gt;[3] MedCity - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.medcityhq.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;medcityhq.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-11-16-essex-the-uks-optimal-location-for-life-sciences-and-health-technology-companies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-11-16-essex-the-uks-optimal-location-for-life-sciences-and-health-technology-companies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-11-16-essex-the-uks-optimal-location-for-life-sciences-and-health-technology-companies.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Essex UK Health Technology Cluster&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/imageedit_1_3094217944_600.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px; height: 170px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a b&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;usiness location, Essex UK provides life sciences and health technology companies with significant 'value adding' advantages, combined with a substantially reduced cost base...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life sciences is a 'high-value' industry sector, typically characterised by high levels of innovation, R&amp;amp;D, market growth and profitability, as well as competition. As a consequence, businesses in the sector considering locations for expansion often prioritise ‘value advantages’ over cost minimisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do we mean by 'value advantages'?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Chesterford RP&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/Chesterford_RP_1_700.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 300px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;In the context of business locations, 'value advantages' are factors that enable businesses to gain competitive edge, and maximise profitability, through innovation and differentiation rather than competing solely on cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For life sciences companies, this typically means being able to access the best research, service providers and highly skilled people, as well as specialised laboratory accommodation and funding solutions. In turn, this drives industry agglomeration (or 'clustering') in 'hub' locations, as people, businesses and R&amp;amp;D organisations co-locate to create and access value advantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The business benefits of life science hubs...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astra Zeneca provides a recent example of agglomeration in the UK life sciences sector. In 2013, the company announced the relocation of its UK R&amp;amp;D operations to Cambridge from a &lt;em&gt;lower cost&lt;/em&gt; UK location. Why? In the words of the company, &lt;em&gt;'The move&lt;/em&gt; [provides] &lt;em&gt;easier access to world-class talent and opportunities for collaboration and partnerships'&lt;/em&gt;, creating &lt;em&gt;'a more vibrant environment that puts science and the patient at the heart of everything the company does'&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;. In other words, &lt;em&gt;more added value&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;And the downside...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there's a downside to industry agglomeration: as organisations and people concentrate at hubs like Cambridge and London, costs increase, sometimes astronomically. That's the point at which businesses must decide whether their optimal location is at the heart of the cluster, or, perhaps, in a 'hinterland' location that combines easy access to the hub with a reduced cost base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The optimal UK life sciences business location...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the UK's 'Greater South East' life sciences cluster, the county of Essex is proving to be the optimal business location for an increasing number of life sciences companies. From Essex, both Cambridge and London can be reached in less than 1 hour, providing businesses with direct access to two of the world's top-ten ranked life sciences universities, and a specialist workforce of more than 40,000 people. &lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Science Village Building&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/CRP3,_Science_Village_Bldg_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 267px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Essex offers other, intrinsic benefits as a life sciences business location. The county's own industry cluster displays competencies across a breadth of life sciences and health technology areas, including medical technology, biotechnology, advanced electronics, pharmaceuticals and 'big data' analytics. And companies can find specialist accommodation at state-of-the art research and business parks, offering motorway and air connectivity that city locations typically can't match. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in Essex, these value-adding advantages are combined with a significantly reduced cost base – delivering potentially massive property and labour cost savings versus Cambridge, London and other leading UK and European life sciences and health technology locations. This means that companies can enjoy the advantages of a world-class business location without the high-cost downside. And it explains why leading companies, including CellCentric, Clement Clarke International, Olympus and Charles River Laboratories have chosen to locate, and expand, within Essex's life sciences and health technology cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FIND OUT MORE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;../index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;INVEST Essex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to find out more about the Essex UK Health Technology Cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[1] &lt;/sup&gt;Astra Zeneca 2013,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[2] &lt;/sup&gt;LSCC Consortium, 2015&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-10-11-essex-uk-and-global-transport-connectivity-for-high-technology-businesses.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-10-11-essex-uk-and-global-transport-connectivity-for-high-technology-businesses</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-10-11-essex-uk-and-global-transport-connectivity-for-high-technology-businesses.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cambridge-Essex UK High-Technology cluster&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/CEUHTC_icon_landscape_600.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; height: 170px; width: 600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Direct access to Cambridge, London and Stansted airport…&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/Essex_Map_700.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 317px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;A range of location advantages are attracting high-tech businesses to Essex UK, including the county’s technology cluster, specialist workforce and cost advantages. But Essex’s optimal geographical location and transport connectivity are consistently amongst the key benefits cited by companies expanding in the county.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fast access to London, Cambridge and major UK airports…&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essex’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://investessex.co.uk/studies/place-studies/harlow-enterprise-zone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Harlow Enterprise Zone&lt;/a&gt; (CM17 postcode) exemplifies the county’s location advantages for high-technology businesses. Strategically located at junction 7 of the M11 motorway, the site provides occupants with access to the global ‘tech hub’ cities of London and Cambridge, as well as London Heathrow Airport, in less than 1 hour. London Stansted airport can be accessed by road in just 14 minutes. [1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Drive times from Harlow, Essex&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/HT3_Drive_Times.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px; height: 267px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fast access to UK technology locations…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essex’s proximity to London and the M25 provides businesses with fast access to southern England’s key high-technology locations, as well as continental European markets via the Channel Tunnel &lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr bgcolor=&quot;#307b33&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#FFFFFF;&quot;&gt;From Harlow (CM17) to:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#FFFFFF;&quot;&gt;Drive Time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#FFFFFF;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color:#307b33;&quot;&gt;Distance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cambridge (Cambridgeshire)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;43 mins&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;37 miles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr bgcolor=&quot;#e3e3e3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;London&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;57 mins&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;28 miles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dover (Eurotunnel)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.35 hrs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;89 miles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr bgcolor=&quot;#e3e3e3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Oxford (Oxfordshire)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.42 hrs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;85 miles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Reading (Berkshire)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.36 hrs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;76 miles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr bgcolor=&quot;#e3e3e3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;Basingstoke (Hampshire)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.40 hrs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;84 miles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Crawley (W Sussex)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.14 hrs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;62 miles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Global air connectivity via London Stansted and Heathrow airports…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For international business travellers, Essex provides fast, comprehensive global air connectivity - from London Stansted, London Heathrow and four other London airports, all accessible within 1 hour: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;10&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr bgcolor=&quot;#e3e3e3&quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London Stansted&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#307b33;&quot;&gt;Essex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;			- 150 destinations&lt;br /&gt;			- European connectivity&lt;br /&gt;			- UK’s 4th busiest airport&lt;br /&gt;			- From Harlow (by road): 14 mins / 13 miles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;10&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;background-color: rgb(227, 227, 227);&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London Heathrow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#307b33;&quot;&gt;UK Hub Airport&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;			- 185 destinations; 84 countries&lt;br /&gt;			- Global connectivity&lt;br /&gt;			- Europe’s busiest airport&lt;br /&gt;			- From Harlow (by road): 54 mins / 51 miles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&quot;10&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;background-color: rgb(227, 227, 227);&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other London Airports&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#307b33;&quot;&gt;(from Harlow, by road):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;			London Southend: 52 mins / 35 miles&lt;br /&gt;			London City: 32 mins / 22 miles&lt;br /&gt;			London Luton: 49 mins / 42 miles      &lt;br /&gt;			London Gatwick: 1 hr / 58 miles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Unrivalled multimodal freight transport connectivity…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For industrial businesses, Essex’s ‘UK Multimodal Gateway’ provides freight transport infrastructure that is unrivalled within the UK:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essex’s multimodal freight transport hub incorporates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 Sea Ports:&lt;/strong&gt; Handling containers and all other all cargo types&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 Rail Freight Terminals:&lt;/strong&gt; Providing fast connections to UK and European markets&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 London Airports:&lt;/strong&gt; Accessible within 1 hour&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct Motorway Links:&lt;/strong&gt; Providing fast access to UK and European markets&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Find out more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;../index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;INVEST Essex&lt;/a&gt; to find out more about Essex as the optimal location for your high-technology business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[1] Google Maps, 2015&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-09-13-education-and-innovation-how-essex-uk-is-securing-the-future-of-its-high-technology-businesses.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-09-13-education-and-innovation-how-essex-uk-is-securing-the-future-of-its-high-technology-businesses</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-09-13-education-and-innovation-how-essex-uk-is-securing-the-future-of-its-high-technology-businesses.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cambridge-Essex UK High Tech cluster&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/CEUHTC_icon_landscape_600.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px; height: 170px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For high technology companies, maintaining a competitive edge requires an innovative approach to education and skills development. In Essex, employers and education providers are working together to show how it’s done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Raytheon&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/Raytheon_Diversity_Image_at_Demo_Center_700.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 299px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;From communications systems to medical devices and more, businesses have become increasingly reliant on high technology, demanding new solutions to meet challenges within their sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to fulfil this demand, high-technology companies face a challenge: not only to keep developing new innovations, but to keep developing the skills of the people who work for them too, now and for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raytheon.co.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Raytheon&lt;/a&gt; – an Essex-based technology and innovation leader specialising in defence, civil government and cybersecurity solutions, has found this to be the case... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The ability to attract and retain appropriately skilled employees is a strategic imperative to delivering competitive advantage,” &lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suzanne Jude, Head of Strategy, Raytheon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, in Essex, it’s a challenge education providers and high-technology businesses are rising to, together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collaborative training and education…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the high-technology industry bridges multiple market sectors, from defence and aerospace to healthcare and automotive, a collaborative approach to training and education is vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://essexpartnership.org/content/essex-employment-and-skills-board&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Essex Employment and Skills Board (ESB),&lt;/a&gt; chaired by Raytheon’s Suzanne Jude, was set up for this purpose, bringing together employers, educators and local government to give Essex ‘a real voice in shaping skills provision.’ &lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what other educational resources does Essex offer? And how does their provision help high-technology businesses in the county?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Specialist technology education provision…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sir Charles Kao University Technical College&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/Sir_Charles_Kao_UTC_Building_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 300px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Essex is home to multiple, high-ranking education establishments that have forged strong links with high-technology industry, including the UK’s first college of advanced technology - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.procat.ac.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PROCAT&lt;/a&gt; (Prospects College of Advanced Technology).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sircharleskaoutc.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sir Charles Kao University Technical College&lt;/a&gt; in Harlow combines practical, academic education and training linked to the workplace, and has built its curriculum around &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sircharleskaoutc.com/about/specialisms/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;technical specialisms&lt;/a&gt; such as Smart Environments and Medical Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, through their close links with Essex-based businesses, both colleges offer adult learning opportunities, industry-linked projects, apprenticeships and traineeships, relevant to the needs of local employers such as Raytheon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The strength of Essex’s further education providers is that they are responsive to employers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both PROCAT and the Sir Charles Kao UTC put employers at the heart of their delivery. This means taking time to understand what works best and responding accordingly.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suzanne Jude, Head of Strategy, Raytheon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;And high-ranking research universities…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;University of Essex &quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/Uni_of_essex_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 300px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;The region’s higher education providers align their teaching specialisms with the requirements of Essex’s high-technology businesses, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.essex.ac.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;University of Essex&lt;/a&gt; – a world top 2% ranked university &lt;sup&gt;[3]&lt;/sup&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.essex.ac.uk/study/pg/masters/default.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;offers post-graduate courses&lt;/a&gt; in areas including Telecommunication and Information Systems and Cloud Computing, at its School of Computer Science and Electronic Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University is also a ‘UK top 20’ university for Research Excellence &lt;sup&gt;[4]&lt;/sup&gt;, with specialisms in a range of key high-technology disciplines, such as Big Data, Radio, Radar and Electromagnetics, and Optical and Semiconductor Devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Skills for success&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With its collaborative approach to meeting skill requirements, leading educational establishments and proximity to London and Cambridge, Essex means business for high-technology companies such as Raytheon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“From our experience of working in other parts of the country and internationally, Essex has developed a truly innovative, evidence-based, responsive approach to skills. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This gives us the confidence that a future workforce is being developed, our needs are understood and that employers have a central role.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suzanne Jude, Head of Strategy, Raytheon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td height=&quot;80&quot;&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;h3&gt;FIND OUT MORE&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;../index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;INVEST Essex&lt;/a&gt; to find out more about the Cambridge-Essex UK High-Technology Cluster.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[1] Interview with Suzanne Jude, Raytheon, February 2016&lt;br /&gt;[2] Essex Partnership: Essex Employment and Skills Board: &lt;a href=&quot;http://essexpartnership.org/content/essex-employment-and-skills-board&quot;&gt;http://essexpartnership.org/content/essex-employment-and-skills-board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[3] Times Higher Education:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.timeshighereducation.com/world-university-rankings/2015/reputation-ranking#!/page/0/length/25&quot;&gt;https://www.timeshighereducation.com/world-university-rankings/2015/reputation-ranking#!/page/0/length/25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[4] Times Higher Education: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.timeshighereducation.com/sites/default/files/Attachments/2014/12/17/x/o/z/sub-14-01.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.timeshighereducation.com/sites/default/files/Attachments/2014/12/17/x/o/z/sub-14-01.pdf&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-07-19-essex-the-uks-optimal-location-for-high-technology-businesses.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-07-19-essex-the-uks-optimal-location-for-high-technology-businesses</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-07-19-essex-the-uks-optimal-location-for-high-technology-businesses.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cambridge-Essex UK High-TechnologyCluster&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/CEUHTC_icon_landscape_600.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/CambridgeEssexGraphic2-META-675px.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 675px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;[1]THE World University Rankings, 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;[2] UK Research Excellence Framework  (REF), 2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;[3] Academic Ranking of World Universities, 2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;[4] Oxford Economics/London &amp;amp; Partners, 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;[5] Cambridge Network, 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;[6] ONS/Nomis, 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;[7] Oxford Economics/London &amp;amp; Partners, 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;[8] Colliers, 2015 (Office Rents)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;[9] Google Maps, 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;Find out more&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;../index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;INVEST Essex&lt;/a&gt; to find out more about the Cambridge-Essex UK High-Technology Cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-04-26-introducing-cambridge-essex-uk-a-world-class-high-technology-cluster.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-04-26-introducing-cambridge-essex-uk-a-world-class-high-technology-cluster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-04-26-introducing-cambridge-essex-uk-a-world-class-high-technology-cluster.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cambridge-Essex UK high technology cluster &quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/CEUHTC_icon_landscape_600.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px; height: 170px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.6;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Advanced electronics manufacturing in Essex&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/e2v_people_at_work_700.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 300px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Everyone with an interest in the technology sector has heard of the UK’s ‘Cambridge Cluster’. According to the University of Cambridge, the city is home to ‘Europe’s largest technology cluster’, with more than 50,000 people employed by around 1,500 technology-based firms. Together, these companies generate annual revenues in excess of £13 billion [1].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So isn’t it a little audacious to speak of the Cambridge-Essex UK High-Technology Cluster?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It certainly seems so, until you look at the facts…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essex is the county adjacent to Cambridgeshire, providing businesses with direct access to all the world-class research and knowledge that Cambridge has to offer. But Essex’s high-technology sector is far more than just a spill over of the Cambridge Cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to ONS data [2], Essex is home to some of the highest concentrations of high-technology industry in the UK. For advanced electronics manufacturing, the key Essex locations of Harlow and Maldon show higher industry concentrations than both Cambridge and South Cambridgeshire (home to several of the Cambridge Cluster’s science and technology parks). For ‘medical instruments manufacturing’, Harlow and Southend (also in Essex) surpass South Cambridgeshire. In summary, there’s a single, contiguous Cambridge-Essex UK High-Technology Cluster, and Essex is a powerful partner within it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Always at the forefront of advanced electronics technologies…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Selex radar&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/Selex_GRIFO-Radar_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 299px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;To put it simply, Essex is a leading location for advanced electronics businesses because it always has been. The county’s leadership in radio frequency-based technologies started with Marconi at the end of the nineteenth century. And it continues to this day, with companies including BAE Systems, Finmeccanica and e2v serving high-technology sectors including aerospace, defence, space, healthcare and advanced automotive. It may come as no surprise that many of these businesses can trace their Essex roots directly back to the Marconi Company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Essex high-technology advantage: added value with massive cost savings…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Essex has world-class high-technology credentials in its own right. But the county also offers cost and connectivity advantages that, together, make it the location of choice for expanding high-technology businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Harlow Enterprise Zone&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/Harlow_ez_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 267px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;From strategic Essex locations like Harlow Enterprise Zone (M11, junction 7), both London and Cambridge can be accessed by road in less than 1 hour [3]. That means direct access to Europe’s business capital, two global technology hubs and three of the world’s ‘top ten’ ranked universities (Cambridge, University College London and Imperial College London – all excelling in engineering, electronics and ICT research).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, uniquely within the UK, Essex combines these value-adding advantages with a significantly reduced cost base – delivering potentially massive property and labour cost savings versus Cambridge, London and other leading UK and European technology locations [4] [5]. That means that high-technology businesses can scale-up manufacturing and R&amp;amp;D operations in an optimal location, without the high-cost downside. And it explains why leading businesses including Raytheon and Arrow Electronics are, right now, choosing to expand in Essex– at the heart of the Cambridge-Essex UK High-Technology Cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FIND OUT MORE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;INVEST Essex&lt;/a&gt; to find out more about the Cambridge-Essex UK High-Technology Cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] University of Cambridge, Research: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cam.ac.uk/research/innovation-at-cambridge/the-cambridge-cluster&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.cam.ac.uk/research/innovation-at-cambridge/the-cambridge-cluster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[2] ONS, Location Quotients by Industry, 2011 (SIC Codes C26 and C325)&lt;br /&gt;[3] Google Maps, 2015&lt;br /&gt;[4] ONS, Nomis&lt;br /&gt;[5] Colliers, 2015: Comparison of prime office costs. Averages of all surveyed Essex, Cambridge &amp;amp; London locations.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-04-05-the-london-advantage-without-the-costs-the-london-essex-uk-finance-corridor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-28T15:26:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-04-05-the-london-advantage-without-the-costs-the-london-essex-uk-finance-corridor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/28/2016-04-05-the-london-advantage-without-the-costs-the-london-essex-uk-finance-corridor.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;London Essex UK finance corridor&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/LEFC_Icon_V2.0-META_RGB_600px_.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px; height: 179px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;London is a world-leading centre of Financial and Professional Services and ‘Europe’s Business Capital’ [1]. But what, precisely, is the key to the city’s success? And what does this mean for financial services businesses considering lower cost UK locations beyond the London hub? [2]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Key to London’s Success in Financial Services: Agglomeration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;People at work in Essex&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/img074_700.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 229px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;One word, perhaps more than any other, explains why London has grown to be the Financial Services powerhouse it is today. And that word is ‘agglomeration’. But what does it really mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, agglomeration is the concentration of an industry’s skills, markets, services infrastructure and knowledge in one place, creating an environment that facilitates the sector’s sustained growth and prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In London, an established concentration of financial services businesses has attracted yet more companies seeking specialised suppliers and customers. And it has attracted the sector’s best workers in large numbers, seeking a broad range of opportunities for career progression. These concentrations have had a number of virtuous effects that have stimulated a ‘snowball effect’ of further growth: the efficient matching of workers to job vacancies; increased competition, resulting in cost-effective, high quality services; an ‘atmosphere’ infused with financial knowledge and information – all reinforcing London’s competitive advantage as a financial services hub. [2]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;But London’s Success Comes at a Price…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there’s another effect of agglomeration that’s far less desirable for businesses: high costs, notably of properties and people. And there’s inevitably a point at which companies will decide that, for certain business functions and operations, being located in the London hub can no longer be justified on cost grounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;People at work&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/IE6_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 300px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Typically, this is the point at which hard decisions have to be made – weighing up the benefits of reducing overheads with the costs of locating away from London. And those costs can be significant: difficulties finding the right, skilled workers; losing the ‘face-to-face’ contact with suppliers and customers that binds business relationships; losing access to the knowledge and information networks that energise London’s financial services sector and continually build workforce expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;But There is Another Way…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact is that ensuring business competitiveness doesn’t have to involve a binary choice between high and rising costs in the London hub or the loss of London’s agglomeration advantages in lower-cost, more remote UK locations. Because London’s financial services sector reaches beyond the limits of the city into the capital’s hinterland, without respect for artificial administrative boundaries. And nowhere is this truer than in the case of the London-Essex UK Finance Corridor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Best of Both Worlds for Finance Businesses…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;London - Essex UK finance corridor&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/London-Essex-Finance-Corridor_GREENS_RGB.jpg&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 20.8px; width: 400px; height: 302px; float: right; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The London-Essex UK Finance Corridor extends eastwards from the City of London along major road and rail routes, incorporating the key Essex towns of Brentwood, Chelmsford, Colchester, Basildon and Southend-on-Sea. These towns provide businesses with transport connectivity to the City of London in as little as 28 minutes [3] combined with office rental costs that are 74% lower than those in the City [4]. Proximity to London delivers workforce benefits too: Essex’s large, local financial services workforce is complemented by highly skilled Essex-based London commuters, and access to London’s vast financial services labour pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Corridor is, as such, an intrinsic extension of London’s world-leading financial services cluster, but without the ‘high-cost’ downside. That’s why it’s been selected as a business location by leading financial services companies including Liverpool Victoria, RSA, Cofunds, First Data and International Financial Data Services (IFDS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in an increasingly competitive business environment, with more focus on cost minimisation than ever before, the business case may well stack up for your company too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FIND OUT MORE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;../index.html&quot;&gt;INVEST Essex&lt;/a&gt; to find out more about property, people and support for your expanding financial services business in Essex, UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[1] Deloitte 2014. London Futures: London Crowned Business Capital of Europe&lt;br /&gt;[2] London’s Central Business District: Its Global Importance. GLA Economics, 2008&lt;br /&gt;[3] The Trainline Europe&lt;br /&gt;[4] Colliers, 2015&lt;br /&gt;[5] London's Place in the World of Finance: A Supply-side Approach: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lboro.ac.uk/gawc/rb/rb60.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.lboro.ac.uk/gawc/rb/rb60.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title type="html">Essex Company Awarded Gbp1 05 Million Towards Improving Treatment For Diabetes Care</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/17/essex-company-awarded-GBP1-05-million-towards-improving-treatment-for-diabetes-care.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Essex Company Awarded Gbp1 05 Million Towards Improving Treatment For Diabetes Care" /><published>2017-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/17/essex-company-awarded-GBP1-05-million-towards-improving-treatment-for-diabetes-care</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/17/essex-company-awarded-GBP1-05-million-towards-improving-treatment-for-diabetes-care.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Diabetes care&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/Diabetes_care_700.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 299px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Arecor Ltd, a leading biopharmaceutical company, has been awarded £1.05 million towards its development of a ready to use glucagon pen for diabetic patients. The funding will support continued preclinical development of Arecor’s proprietary stable liquid glucagon that will replace glucagon powder and speed up the treatment process for diabetic patients with hypoglycaemia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Using Arecor's technology, we have been able to solve the very significant and elusive formulation challenge of developing a stable liquid glucagon product that will enable us to deliver a ready-to-use pen to rescue a hypo more quickly and effectively.'&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Sarah Howell, CEO, Arecor Limited&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Improving and simplifying diabetes care process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Diabetes care&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/proper-testing_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 299px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Arecor have been working with the Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation (JDRF) charity and patient groups to ensure their pen significantly improves and simplifies the administration of this life saving treatment and reduces a major source of anxiety for those living with type 1 and 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funding that has been awarded to Arecor from Innovate UK’s funding competition will be used for initiation human trials of the product. The funding is part of a government funding competition which has awarded over £1.8 billion to innovative science projects since 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;'We are delighted to receive this prestigious award from Innovate UK which will support the acceleration of our proprietary glucagon rescue treatment towards the clinic and first-in-human phase 1 trials”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Sarah Howell, CEO, Arecor Limited&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Focusing on improved treatments for diabetes care&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://investessex.co.uk/studies/case-studies/arecor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Research laboratory&quot; src=&quot;http://www.investessex.co.uk/uploads/about/research-lab_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 300px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Arecor&lt;/a&gt;, a spin out from Unilever in 2007, is developing a portfolio of products to enable improved treatments for diabetes care. Arecor has partnered with the world’s largest pharmaceutical and biotech companies such as Glaxo Smith Kline (GSK), Genzyme, GALVmed, to enable previously impossible delivery and use options for biologics. In over 90 per cent of the cases – Arecor’s technology can enable…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;solid-to-liquid re-formulations&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;improved stability&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;high-concentration delivery, e.g. 200+ mg/ml&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;co-formulation of incompatible components&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Expanding facilities for research and development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Chesterford Research Park&quot; src=&quot;../uploads/blog/Chesterford_RP_1_400.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 300px; margin-left: 2px; margin-right: 2px; float: right;&quot; /&gt;Arecor is the latest company to move to &lt;a href=&quot;http://investessex.co.uk/studies/place-studies/chesterford-research-park&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chesterford Research Park&lt;/a&gt; where they have recently signed a five year lease on a 10,000sq ft (929sq m) facility having outgrown their 5000 sq ft facility on the Cambridge Science Park. This is twice the size of the company’s previous premises and allows the company to expand their research and development (R&amp;amp;D) facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company joined major bioscience players such as AstraZeneca and Domainex who have all chosen Chesterford as the base from which to advance their research and development. Chesterford is a key location within the ‘London-Stansted-Cambridge Corridor’ – identified as an emerging growth area for life sciences businesses. These location advantages are combining to make Essex a significant centre of life sciences research and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Working with INVEST Essex&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INVEST Essex worked with Arecor on their choice of site; a 10,000sq ft (929sq m) facility incorporating an office and a research and development (R&amp;amp;D) space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INVEST Essex also introduced Arecor to Uttlesford District Council who were able to provide support to the company with their Business Development Rate Relief Scheme. Arecor are now in the process of developing commercial collaborations which INVEST Essex will offer support with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on INVEST Essex see &lt;a href=&quot;../index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diabetes.co.uk/news/2017/feb/government-awards-million-pound-funding-for-ready-to-use-glucagon-pen-91580000.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Diabetes&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.genengnews.com/gen-news-highlights/arecor-wins-innovate-uk-grant-to-develop-liquid-glucagon-for-severe-hypoglycemia/81253809&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GEN News&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Arecor Ltd, a leading biopharmaceutical company, has been awarded £1.05 million towards its development of a ready to use glucagon pen for diabetic patients. The funding will support continued preclinical development of Arecor’s proprietary stable liquid glucagon that will replace glucagon powder and speed up the treatment process for diabetic patients with hypoglycaemia.
“Using Arecor's technology, we have been able to solve the very significant and elusive formulation challenge of developing a stable liquid glucagon product that will enable us to deliver a ready-to-use pen to rescue a hypo more quickly and effectively.'Dr Sarah Howell, CEO, Arecor Limited
Improving and simplifying diabetes care process
Arecor have been working with the Juvenile Diabetes Research Foundation (JDRF) charity and patient groups to ensure their pen significantly improves and simplifies the administration of this life saving treatment and reduces a major source of anxiety for those living with type 1 and 2 diabetes.
The funding that has been awarded to Arecor from Innovate UK’s funding competition will be used for initiation human trials of the product. The funding is part of a government funding competition which has awarded over £1.8 billion to innovative science projects since 2007.
'We are delighted to receive this prestigious award from Innovate UK which will support the acceleration of our proprietary glucagon rescue treatment towards the clinic and first-in-human phase 1 trials”.Dr Sarah Howell, CEO, Arecor Limited
Focusing on improved treatments for diabetes care
Arecor, a spin out from Unilever in 2007, is developing a portfolio of products to enable improved treatments for diabetes care. Arecor has partnered with the world’s largest pharmaceutical and biotech companies such as Glaxo Smith Kline (GSK), Genzyme, GALVmed, to enable previously impossible delivery and use options for biologics. In over 90 per cent of the cases – Arecor’s technology can enable…
solid-to-liquid re-formulationsimproved stabilityhigh-concentration delivery, e.g. 200+ mg/mlco-formulation of incompatible components
Expanding facilities for research and development
Arecor is the latest company to move to Chesterford Research Park where they have recently signed a five year lease on a 10,000sq ft (929sq m) facility having outgrown their 5000 sq ft facility on the Cambridge Science Park. This is twice the size of the company’s previous premises and allows the company to expand their research and development (R&amp;amp;D) facilities.
The company joined major bioscience players such as AstraZeneca and Domainex who have all chosen Chesterford as the base from which to advance their research and development. Chesterford is a key location within the ‘London-Stansted-Cambridge Corridor’ – identified as an emerging growth area for life sciences businesses. These location advantages are combining to make Essex a significant centre of life sciences research and innovation.
Working with INVEST Essex
INVEST Essex worked with Arecor on their choice of site; a 10,000sq ft (929sq m) facility incorporating an office and a research and development (R&amp;amp;D) space.
INVEST Essex also introduced Arecor to Uttlesford District Council who were able to provide support to the company with their Business Development Rate Relief Scheme. Arecor are now in the process of developing commercial collaborations which INVEST Essex will offer support with.
For more information on INVEST Essex see here.
Source [Diabetes] [GEN News]</summary></entry></feed>
